# **Fabian van Noort**



I research people and products, to make products work for people.

otrecht, NL mail@fabianvannoort.nl https://www.linkedin.com/in/fabianvannoort/

# **Summary**

Fabian is a UX researcher with 9 years of agency experience serving different industries. He is a dedicated team player with an analytical mind, a strong product sense and a fondness for qualitative and quantitative research. His mission is to research people and products, to make products work for people.

## **Expertise**

### Promoting human-centered product development

- Coaching product teams on human-centered design and UX research through collaboration and story-telling in (multi)national organisations;
- Identifying product opportunities, by amplifying the voice of the customer in collaboration with PMs, designers and other team members;
- Shaping actionable ux research questions, creating research plans, driving projects, structuring and analysing data, deriving actionable insights, presenting compelling stories, prioritising and socialising next steps.

### **Qualitative UX Research**

- Behavioral research methods, such as: (un)moderated usability testing, remote usability testing, eye-tracking, contextual inquiry, guerilla testing;
- Attitudinal research methods, such as: in-depth interviewing, concept testing, diary studies, customer feedback analysis, affinity diagramming.

### **Quantitative UX Research**

- Behavioral research methods, such as: tree testing, first-click testing, fake-door testing, a/b-testing, click-stream analysis, conversion funnel analysis;
- Attitudinal research methods, such as: intercept surveys (CSAT/NPS/CES/UX metrics), user feedback analysis, card sorting, design surveys, Kano, JTBD.

# **Work Experience**

### Senior UX Researcher

Valsplat Apr 2022 — present

- Working embedded with product teams, or driving one-off projects, to inform product decisions;
- Advocating for data-driven human-centered design by coaching products teams on UXR and quantifying user issues and solutions.
- Project lead budget responsibility €200k+, for (multi)national clients such as: Action, Albert Heijn, Brabantia, Etos, Heineken, Hogeschool Inholland,
  Nationale Hypotheek Garantie, Nederlandse Spoorwegen, Nieuwe Schoolfoto, PostNL, Tweakers, Volksbank;

### **UX Researcher**

Valsplat Oct 2016 — Mar 2022

- Preparing research plans with clients, executing research, presenting actionable insights;
- Project lead budget responsibility up to €100k, for (multi)national clients such as: Albert Heijn, Bever (AS Adventure), Brabantia, DELA, Eliza was here, HEMA, KPN, Marktplaats, Philips Hue, PostNL, Sunweb, Tommy Hilfiger, Tweakers, Van Gogh Museum;

### **UX** Designer

Puurpxl Feb 2015 — Oct 2016

- Discovering requirements for clients' new websites and crafting project proposals in collaboration with clients;
- Defining interactions on and between web page templates in Axure RP, in collaboration with visual designers and front-end developers.

### **Education**

MSc. Applied Cognitive Psychology, cum laude

Utrecht University

MSc. Information Studies

University of Amsterdam

### **BSc. Information Sciences**

Utrecht University